come back and today I will show you
outbox pattern in the
event-driven architecture. Very, very
important. It has been asked a lot in
interviews.
And I will also tell you what generally
engineer
tried to answer first. Okay? But those
answers are generally overruled because
there are some gap in those. And what's
the correct answer?
Okay?
So, before we go deep into this outbox
pattern, we first need to understand the
problem which exist. Okay? So,
if you see this, this is the problem
statement which interviewer will provide
you.
Very, very simple
method of a create order when this
endpoint got hit.
What it does it? It first tried to save
in the DB.
Okay? So, the order which has been
received, we are trying to store in DB.
And in the step two, we are also
publishing an
event.
The most common use case in industry.
We have to store in DB and also we have
to publish an event. Nothing special in
this. Okay? So, these two tasks we have
to do in this method.
So,
interviewer will say, "What's the
problem in this?"
So, there is one major flaw in this one.
So, we are writing two separate
independent system. So, this is one
independent system, DB.
And this is another
independent system which is Kafka.
Okay? So, we are trying to write into
two independent system. Okay? So, we can
get problem like DB get succeeded, but
Kafka fails. For example, your DB
order repository.save.
And this got succeeded. This first got
succeeded. Your It is stored in the DB
successfully.
But when you're trying to publish to the
Kafka, that got failed.
This could result in that
the order exists in DB, yes, but no
event published. So, maybe the
downstream components like payment
service, inventory service which rely on
this event,
they will not be able to update their
system. So, it could result into data
inconsistency.
Similarly, what we can have is
Kafka got succeed, but DB got failed.
It's possible, right? If Kafka is able
to publish an event, but DB we don't
have. So, what would happen is all the
downstream like payment, inventory, they
will update their system, but order
doesn't even exist in the DB. So, this
is like more impact than use case one.
So,
this is the problem statement. So,
problem statement would be given to you
only this that what's the problem in
this, then we have to say that, "Okay,
this two issue can come."
And then
actually, the name of this problem is
dual write problem. So, once we have
identified this problem,
the interviewer will say that, "How you
will solve it?"
Okay?
So, I will tell you one two common
answers generally given by engineers,
but it get overruled because they these
answers generally have some gap.
The first answer,
we will use @transactional
plus manual exception throw.
What this solution does? So, we have put
@transactional for DB.
So, what would happen is So, in a step
one, we are writing into the DB.
If this succeeded, we are moving it to
the next step. Now, the Kafka part we
have put into try catch block.
If Kafka got succeeded, well and good.
DB succeeded, Kafka succeeded, good.
But if there any exception happens in
Kafka, it will catch it and throw.
And because of this throw exception,
since it is put under @transactional, it
will roll back the DB also.
So, very high level, this solution looks
good, right? So, DB got succeeded. If
Kafka got succeeded, well and good.
DB fails,
ultimately, it would be rolled back, so
good. DB succeeded, Kafka failed, so it
will throw exception and DB will also
get rolled back.
So, sounds good, right? But there is a
gap.
See this one.
DB
success, well and good.
Kafka template send message sent to the
Kafka broker. Message has sent to the
Kafka broker.
Okay?
But there is some gap in the
acknowledgement received by the
you can say that by the broker. Or the
acknowledgement message has been lost
because of network issue.
Now, what you will what your application
as a producer application will think
that, "Hey,
the message has not been published." But
actually, it is published.
But the acknowledge
packet has been lost in the network, you
can say that because of network issue.
So, you will say that, "Okay, Kafka
publish got failed." You will roll back
it. And when you roll back it,
when you throw exception, you will roll
back the DB also.
But
your Kafka event got published.
Okay? So, the issue is that order does
not exist in DB,
but Kafka event published. You got it?
You got the issue?
At the first glance, everything looks
good, but there is still a gap. So,
that's why this solution generally get
overruled.
The second solution which generally
proposes two phase commit that we will
have a coordinator.
We will have a one prepare
phase.
One for DB, one for Kafka. Both will
participate.
And like normal two phase commit
protocol, right? So, but the
participants are DB and Kafka.
So, they will first say that, "Yes, I'm
ready." Now, in the phase two, they will
commit. And after that, they will
commit. But the problem is this looks
working solution. But the problem is
Kafka do not even support two phase
protocol, two phase commit protocol.
Okay?
So, two phase commit to work,
all participants need to understand this
protocol. And Kafka does not support
2PC.
So,
there is no use to discuss the pros and
cons of this that, "Okay, what would
happen this?"
The thing is Kafka do not understand
this prepare commit and all. So, you
can't add Kafka as one of the
participant itself.
So,
this two
things are overruled.
The solution
which currently widely used in industry
is outbox pattern.
So, idea is
don't write directly to Kafka.
Write to DB first, and then a separate
process read the DB and publish to
Kafka.
Okay? So, now see this.
In this one,
the first step is same.
I am writing to order. I have got the
order. So, order repository to save
order, same. Whatever we were doing
before also, the same. Okay?
Now, in the second one, if you see, I am
not publishing to Kafka.
I have created a new table, outbox
table. Okay? And I am publishing the
event details into that one. So, it's
still the DB
operation only. So, now they can
participate in one transaction.
If any of this fail,
we can roll back successfully.
Okay? So, at this point of time, Kafka
is not involved. Only DB operation.
So, in this outbox pattern,
a new table, you can give any name, but
generally standard is you can give
outbox table outbox name or whatever the
name you want to give.
So, a new table, say outbox table, is
introduced. In that one, what
we need to store the event details,
whatever we have to publish.
So, that we
store into this. And this two now DB
operation can be part of one
transaction.
And now later on,
a separate process
will read from this table and publish to
Kafka.
Again, lot of interview question can be
come to this like what the separate
process? We will come to this one. So,
there are two.
Polar
and CDC.
Okay? I will tell you both.
But at a high level, you got it what the
outbox pattern idea is that we will
create a new table,
new DB table, and that DB table is store
the event details, and a separate
process read from this table, and then
publish to Kafka.
Okay? So, now this become overall
compliant with what we wanted.
So, what is the schema of this outbox
table? It's a normal regular DB table,
and you can like change it according to
your need. You can give any name you
want. Okay? So, but this is generally
high level.
What everyone use? A unique ID.
Okay?
Aggregate type.
Order. Generally, this is used for
determining the topic. Okay? Which topic
it will go.
Event type is order created, order
deleted. Generally, we don't use it
like, but still if your business logic
has to know about like, "Okay,
the order, but what happened to the
order? Order created, order deleted." Or
something you have to send into the
header.
Or you have some business logic on top
of it. So, at least it will give you
more context what happened to the order.
Event type. Okay?
And then aggregate ID. You can consider
that this is act as a key. Okay? This so
that this is very important. So that all
the s-
orders
Let's say all the order which belongs to
customer ID, let's say key is K1.
So all the order
for this key should goes to one
partition so that order get maintained.
Let's say first order created, then
order cancelled.
Then so let's say this two, order
created, order cancelled. So there's a
proper ordering.
So they both should have same key, key
one, key one.
When they have a same key, they then
only they would be goes to the same
partition and when they go to the same
partition, then the order would be
maintained. First order created, then
order cancelled.
Got it? So aggregate ID, you can say
that
used for key.
Then your normal payload which you want
to publish. Created at is published. So
this is optional.
I will tell you its use.
Okay? So but this is something
is customizable depending upon your
business need. But this is the high
level. We can determine the topic name,
we can determine the key, we can
determine the payload.
Okay, that's the same thing I have
explained it here.
And is published is optional. I will
tell you when it is used, when it is not
used.
So outbox table is consumed in two ways.
I told you that outbox table, a separate
process will read the data. Again,
there are two ways this outbox table
data is consumed.
One is polar
or you can say that polling.
Another is CDC, change data capture,
very important.
Okay?
So is published is used in polling, but
in CDC does not used. We'll see that
one.
So let's start first polling and then
later I will also show you the
CDC mechanism also. If you have gone
through the Spring Boot playlist
and in that one I have covered JPA.
So in in that one you will get to know
how to create entity repository, how to
connect with the DB.
So this is the same thing I am doing it
here, nothing is special.
So this is just one controller.
The
request comes to this one.
Then I'm calling this order service.
Okay? And here I have at the rate
transactional.
Now we know that we have to do two
things. First thing is we have to store
into the order DB.
And second we have to store in the
outbox
DB.
So for this two tables, we have entity,
order entity,
outbox entity. Again, please check JPA
topics if you have any doubt what is
entity or how to create repository.
Then for this two entity I have order
repository, outbox repository.
Now the I have dependency here.
And I'm just using it. Order
repository.save order.
And then outbox repository.save outbox
event.
Okay? So outbox event I have created
aggregate type, aggregate ID, event
type, and the payload.
So very very simple. These all are like
just helps in creating the tables and
connecting with the DB.
And this is the application.properties.
If you have gone through the JPA part,
you know that uh
you can connect with So in the JPA part
I have connected with S2DB, but the same
way you can connect with MySQL,
Postgres, anything. So you need to
provide the data source, username,
password, and the driver class. Okay?
So with the same way
we can connect to a Postgres, MySQL, and
any DB which you want.
But this is the
very basic thing we have to write.
So now what we have done till now is in
the outbox table we have the data. Now
we have to write the polar.
The polar should poll the outbox table.
So very simple way
I have written one polar. You can say
that it is just a scheduler.
Okay? I've also covered the scheduler,
how you can write it.
So this is one scheduler
I have annotated with at the rate
schedule.
At what time it should it run is that in
this one I'm controlling. Every two
seconds this will run. Okay?
So every two second it will run. What
I'm doing is in the outbox repository, I
am finding the unpublished event and the
best size is 10. Here I have defined it
in the application.properties.
So outbox prop- in the outbox repository
I have
this method.
Select asterisk from outbox event table,
okay, outbox event in the entity, this
is the table name.
Where published equals to false means it
is not yet published. And order by
created at so that order is maintained.
Limit batch size.
So I am getting 10 record at a time
ordered by created at. Okay? If there is
none, return it.
But once you get it, we have to
publish it. Okay? So that's what I'm
just doing Kafka template.send.
You have a topic,
aggregate ID key, payload.
Okay? Once you have able to publish to
the Kafka, set published to true that
yes, now you are published so that next
run this same record should not be
picked.
And when you published at is time,
just save it. Outbox repository.save
this event.
In catch, why I'm breaking is let's say
I need to follow an order. Let's say
three events for this key.
Now if one event got failed, so it goes
to the catch.
If I do not break it, it will proceed
two and three. Then the order will
break. So if one fail, then you should
not proceed with two and three. That's
why I have put break.
So you can say that this is just a one
basic polar.
And it's very simple to write it.
So you understood the polling technique?
But this polling has so many
disadvantages
and that's where interview will say that
okay,
why s- do you have something better than
polling?
But first we need to understand the
disadvantage of polling. Disadvantage of
polling is
multi-instance handling.
So let's say you have three application,
three instances, instance one, instance
two, instance three. So means three
polar. So this is your polar one, polar
two, polar three. All three will run
together.
So you need to maintain that okay, they
should not pick the same row.
Okay? And if they pick different
different rows, then they should not
break the order. Let's say order
all belongs to one key, one, two, and
key one here three. This can break the
order.
So if it pub- process three, one, and
then one and two later.
So there are many problems comes. So we
have to have like shed lock technique
like concept we have to build out. So we
have to handle the multi-instance
handling.
Then a polling gap. Like here I am
running the scheduler every two second
delay. So even though event is created
at 10, the next poll will run at 10:02
itself. So there is always a delay
depending upon your
what time you are polling.
Okay?
Interval.
Constant DB load. Now let's say that
there is no event at all, but you have
to continuously poll your DB.
Okay? So means you're
consistently putting a load on your DB.
Is there any event? Is there any event?
Is there any event? Even though there is
no event at all.
You have also need to take care of the
DB clean up. So since you are
maintaining a table, outbox event table,
it need to be clean up regularly as its
size will grow rapidly.
Duplicate processing.
What happened is sometime let's say you
have a you have read one row, you have
published also,
but you failed to update to published
published to true. That got failed.
So in the next run again this row would
be picked up and you will publish it
again.
So there are this is very common that
you will publish the same event multiple
times so your consumer need to properly
handle the idempotency.
So there are many challenges with the
polling.
And that's where the change data capture
comes into the picture.
Very very important. So in the next part
I will tell you this one.